<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michiel Bakker</title>
    <link>https://mvbakker.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michiel Bakker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 17:19:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mvbakker.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Cluster - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/k8s-cluster-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 17:19:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/k8s-cluster-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction About a week ago I started learning about K8s. Soon a learned that there are plenty possibilties to run a cluster yourself online (katacoda, play-with-k8s) but I also learned many people installed it themselves on a Raspberry Pi cluster. Challenge accepted!
Below I&amp;rsquo;ll describe why and how I did this (so far). Please note that I am still learning about K8s as well as Ansible, so it could well be that there are other or better ways to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for AWS review</title>
      <link>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/docker-for-aws-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/docker-for-aws-review/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So I stumbled upon this site: Docker for AWS
Basically, Docker created a template to deploy a cluster on AWS easily that takes care, among other things, of the loadbalancing and storage, the two architectural topics that Docker usually leaves up to you to resolve and implement correctly.
Motivation A few weeks ago I decided I wanted to create a highly available container platform on AWS. I was studying then for the Docker Certified Associate exam and wanted to see what it takes to create such a platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenFOAM on a Raspberry Pi cluster</title>
      <link>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/openfoam-on-raspi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/openfoam-on-raspi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>So a couple of months ago I got this crazy idea. I wanted to learn more about OpenFOAM and the supercomputers they use at my university they use for CFD (computational fluid dynamics) calculations. Just a quick introduction, computational fluid dynamics calculations are performed to calculate fluid (air, water etcetera) flows for basically all kinds of stuff (airplanes, cars, wind turbines etcetera). These calculations are often very computational intensive and therefore they are performed on a cluster of computers (often called a supercomputer, but its basically just multiple computers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Self-hosted Nextcloud server</title>
      <link>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/self-hosted-nextcloud-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/self-hosted-nextcloud-server/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about setting up my own cloud service for a while now. I think it is good to be a little selfhosted nowadays. Recently I bought an UP-Board and this little powerfull computer seemed just perfect for this project. In this post I will not walk you through all the steps specifically. However I will show you what manuals and instructions I used and what problems arose during the process and how I solved those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post</title>
      <link>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mvbakker.github.io/blog/my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog!
So far it is rather empty but prepare for some nice posts. Currently I am working on my graduation project so I am a little short on time. However I have got some nice projects laying around which I like to write about on this blog. What kind of projects can you expect?
 My five-node Raspberry Pi 2B cluster (hopefully running OpenFOAM simulations) I am currently working on setting up an OwnCloud server on an UP-board And maybe a post on my experience with Linux so far  As I said, it could take a little time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>